Well, you go two or three weeks and
every day is $20, $30, $50, $120 up. You
just think, "This is relentless. Where
does it end?" Right?
>> And and then it does end and it's either
the very end of a bull market or it's in
an interim phase. And yeah, I think we
are in fact in the interim phase, third,
fourth inning. But thank you. It's about
time. You know, 10 15% lower for gold
and silver. That's in the category of a
gift. That's how I would see it. And we
we're most of the way there already that
>> it moves fast. And by the way, counter
trend moves tend to do that. Uh they're
they're grinding one direction and
they're sharp and short the other
direction.
>> And that's what you're expecting at this
point. You know, after listening to
Morgan Lewis uh talking both at the MWM
meeting and even this morning, we
realize that we're seeing a major regime
change in the monetary system. So I
would imagine your central banks which
have been pushing this market up are
probably going to be buyers after this
correction again
>> and I I think metals are in the early
stages of being normalized as an asset
class amongst global investors as well.
So you know that it is taking a pause
does allow for investors to step in and
again the normalizing of the asset class
is pretty important. It's it's uh
something that's pretty new to most
investors. September ETF flows show that
investors are beginning to take an
interest. Um but yes, it is time for a
correction.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Well, and the other thing
that you've been watching is the
outperformance of silver relative to
gold. That ratio uh we started to see
silver outperform and you started
realizing that was going to change the
market a little bit. Well, and and we
suggested this at the beginning of the
year that you would see confirmation of
a bull trend and an entrance into an
acceleration phase when mining stocks
outperform the physical metals, right?
When there was an increase in ETF flows
and when outperformance of silver
relative to gold occurred. We've had all
three, which is supportive to the
long-term bull case. Though again I
would be more enthusiastic if the gold
silver ratio could break out of the 80s.
Uh it did so for a nancond last week but
has since returned to 85 to1 this week
by the middle of next year. I think it
will be in the mid60s on the ratio.
>> Well and just for the record for those
who are watching this uh you actually
started the recording late this morning
because you moved some of your gold over
to silver when the ratio hit that
number. But uh
>> you know, but I'm also grateful that
I've got a vault plan in the vaulted
program. And you know, the time that it
took for one trade to settle. All I had
to do is refresh the page. Settled
>> and then I went back in and purchased
the silver. Refresh. Settled. There I
have my new ounces in silver. So, um,
no, I was this morning, as a matter of
fact, was the deposit. Yesterday was the
deposit into my vaulted account and the
trade settled this morning at lower
numbers, which I was grateful for,
right? um last year
>> and then you moved over to silver after
that, right? That's right.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Well, you know, it's
probably important too as we go through
these corrections to go back and review
the bigger picture. And Morgan's hard
asset insights, uh Morgan Lewis's hard
asset insights on our website is
something that our our listeners can
read every Saturday morning after he he
posts them on Friday. I would encourage
this weekend's missive is is sort of a
must readad for perspective on how we
see the unfolding bull market in metals
and I I in fact encourage might be too
soft. I insist you take the time to read
Morgan Lewis's hard asset insights this
weekend. Uh nothing short of a
structural monetary regime change unlike
what we've seen unlike anything we've
seen since 1944 and the creation of
Breton Woods. It has positive
implications for the precious metals for
years to come. Uh not so positive if
you're looking at our currency. Uh but
Morgan shares the highlights from our
investor conference in in this week's
HAI. Uh you won't want to miss it.
>> Okay. So let's say we get a 5%
correction say today or tomorrow. Uh
what are you looking for? What would be
typical uh on on a correction after
seeing what we've seen with gold if if
it can be stated?
>> Yeah. Well, first of all, I I think your
core position, you sit tight. You add on
on a correction for late comers to this
bull. I It's just helpful to know that a
10 15% correction is in line with
historical upside pressure alleviation.
You know, things run and run and run
>> and it does pause and so this is this is
a super healthy thing. Morgan ties
together the the policy inclinations of
the current administration which are
explicitly dollar negative and you know
driven by a combination of industrial
policies debt alleviation via inflation.
Uh so again in the broader context a
very strong support for the metals a 15%
a 10% correction uh likely I think
that's at the front edge of a broader
market decline thinking of the S&P and
the NASDAQ for instance and this is
where you you look at risk assets and
risk has been ignored. it won't be
ignored forever. And there are times in
the last 20 years where gold was at the
front edge of a broader decline and then
all of a sudden people rethink risk and
clamor back to own gold shortly
thereafter while you have the remainder
of decline in in the you know in your
equities.
>> Got a question for you. You just came
back from a conference uh and you were
speaking to a group of people who are
relatively informed investors. uh was
there an awareness of the gold market at
at this time?
>> I had assumed given the degree of
education and the involvement in their
direct asset management that they would
have understood the gold market very
well. So I I spoke to a group of 4 to
500 investors. This was last week. And
so I d I dived right into portfolio
composition and precious metals trading
strategies and the best way to navigate.
You were assuming that they knew what
you were talking about.
>> I was assuming that they understood why
gold and silver.
>> The the why I that was obvious. I mean,
we're we're well into a bull market. If
this is third or fourth inning, this is
not, you know, the fresh first pitch of
the game.
What's What don't you know? Of course,
you understand this.
>> One of the top performing assets in all
of the asset structure,
>> arguably the top performing asset. I
you've got miners up 130%.
uh you've got the you know in a range
from 60% for gold 7 over 70% for silver
80 to 83% in the platinum group metals
yeah obviously prior to the correction
but this is what I was sharing with them
last week right
>> and and there was this dumbfounded look
on their face
>> um so 53 years has taught us a few
things I was trying to distill for them
you know more of the why us than why
gold because there is a healthy way to
navigate these markets and to be able to
compound ounces takes
the proper portfolio composition on the
front edge
>> and a little historic knowledge.
>> Yeah. So, metals hit an all-time high
last week, retested those highs
yesterday for a nice double top and
across the crowd there were only a few
that knew anything about it.
>> Isn't that typical? The thing is that's
amazing is gold is in the news now yet
people are still giving you blank
stairs.
>> Yeah. So, where are the metals trading?
Blank stairs. What are the returns year
to date? blank stairs.
>> Interest in crypto off the charts.
Interest in real estate and a host of
other highly illquid assets very
interested and that set the tone for
every conversation. It was absolutely
fascinating. Only one conversation at
this conference stood out. A corporate
credit analyst in the audience concerned
about market liquidity flipping fast in
the months ahead.
>> Uh very aware of the metals market and
he's also a routine reader of the credit
bubble bulletin. Ah, well, there you go.
No wonder risk awareness was otherwise
very low.
And it makes sense that gold was not on
their radar because they're not thinking
about risk. They're not thinking about
wealth insurance. And plain and simple,
that's what metals are is wealth
insurance. You tell me if risk, the
awareness of risk is priced into the
financial markets today.